Summary

I am a software developer who has a passion for finding efficient and effective solutions to complex puzzles. My motivations are inspired by a deep enthusiasm for applying my critical thinking skills to new and ambitious projects. I excel at problem solving in a fast paced, challenging environment.

Skills

LANGUAGES Ruby JavaScript	FRAMEWORKS Rails ActiveRecord	TDD RSpec Capybara	TOOLS/OTHER PostgreSQL Git
HTML CSS	jQuery Node.js	Mocha Chai	Heroku Agile
SQL	Express.js	Minitest Selenium	Development Pivotal Tracker Waffle

Projects

Rails Engine

URL: https://github.com/CjMoore/rails_engine

Rails Engine is an API that uses RESTful routes to expose sales data, as well as a number of business endpoints that return calculated data.

- Some of the challenges of this project were learning ActiveRecord, and using it to make intricate queries and do complex business analytics.
- I made this project collaboratively with a partner. We separated responsibility and primarily worked independently, but ultimately when we put all the pieces together it was very consistent.
- Tech Stack: Rails, Ruby, PostgreSQL, ActiveRecord, jBuilder, RSpec.

Sentiment Analyzer

URL: https://info-is-everywhere.herokuapp.com/

Sentiment Analyzer uses IBM's Watson API to analyze the tone of a users input and display the returned data on a graph.

- One of the biggest challenges I faced on this project was visualizing the data returned from the Watson API. I used the HighCharts library to create and customize the data visualization.
- Tech Stack: Rails, Ruby, JavaScript, Watson API, HighCharts, RSpec

Quantified Self

URL: https://cjmoore.github.io/quantified-self/

Quantified Self is a food diary application built with an independent back-end which is hosted on Heroku, and a front-end hosted on github pages.

- This was my first functional Node.js/Express application
- Tech Stack: JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Knex, PostgreSQL, Mocha, Chai, Webpack

Contact

■ mooc123@gmail.com

cimoore.github.io

(202)531-3141

in /in/charlotte-moore O cimoore

Education

Turing School of Software & Design

2016-2017

Back-End Engineering

University of Maryland **Baltimore County**

2012-2013 Philosophy

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

2009-2012

Chemistry, Philosophy

Employment

Chicken Charlies Rotisserie and Grill August 2016

June 2014 to

Manager

• I started as a delivery driver, and through my commitment to quality customer service I quickly became an essential member of the team and was promoted to the position of manager.

Mountain Air Systems

February 2014 to May 2014

Receptionist

• In this client facing position I was responsible for providing excellent customer service and administrative support.

Employment Solutions

May 2013 to December 2013

Administrative Assistant

• In this position I was responsible for providing technical and administrative support to a leading EEOC investigator.